ZACHARY CAVINESS

253-376-3810

zacharycaviness@gmail. com

2117 Sturgeon Dr, Marysville, WA 98271

Profile

Honorably Discharged as an E-5 Petty Officer from the United States Navy, I have 5 years of sustained and superior performance as an Aegis Computer Network Technician, Work Center Supervisor and Casualty Control Coordinator. My intentions are to transfer years of valuable naval education, leadership and experience into the private sector.

Experience

Work Center Supervisor — 2020-Present

Manage three expert technicians in troubleshooting, maintenance and repair procedures utilizing technical publications to enable the organization to have maximum mission readiness and accountability.

Combat Systems Officer of the Watch - 2019-Present

Coordinate casualty control to ensure critical network infrastructure, navigational equipment and auxiliary systems are constantly operational and to support reconfiguration options if necessary, as well as deconflict maintenance scheduling issues and issuing power panel tag-outs to ensure personnel safety.

Aegis Computer Networking Technician — 2016- Present

Knowledge in operation, maintenance, and troubleshooting of UNIX based systems and Cisco devices as well as data display and recording systems, servos and synchros and integrated weapon systems components with an understanding of radar theory and operation.

Education

Naval Station Great Lakes, Center for Surface Combat Systems, Great Lakes, Illinois

Naval Surface Warfare Center Dahlgren, Aegis Training and Readiness Center, Dahlgren, Virginia (Naval Enlistment Code 1318,1348/V36A)

Skills

- Methodical Technician and Leader
- Communicates effectively and efficiently
- Detail Oriented
- Team Player
- Motivated and Quick Learner

Qualifications

- Combat Systems Officer of the Watch
- Active DOD Secret Clearance
- Work Center Supervisor
- Pending Network+ Certification (February 25th, 2021)
- Pending Security+ Certification (April 20th, 2021)

References

Available upon request.